<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Digital History</title>
    <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Digital History</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 22:31:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotly</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/plotly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 22:31:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/plotly/</guid>
      <description>     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital History for April 4th</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-april-4th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:11:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-april-4th/</guid>
      <description>Digital History for April 4, 2018 “Visualization and Historical Arguments” by John Theibault I couldn’t help but think back to some of the awesome visualizations we have already been through in class. The Napoleon advance into Russia was a happy memory. Then my smile was quickly wiped off my face as he brought up the accuracy of graphs and if they are valid to the information around it. I can’t say I have read anything that didn’t match with the visual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carto</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/carto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 22:10:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/carto/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital History for March 28th</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-march-28th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:03:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-march-28th/</guid>
      <description>Digital History for March 28, 2018 Stephen Robertson, “Putting Harlem on the Map” I was a little surprised that there was no mention of income level or the variances thereof. Robertson did mention crime, which goes hand in hand with crime. He did mention a man stealing to pay for his wife’s medical needs but that means that there is a poverty issue. The last two weeks have had me deep in Omaha neighborhoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital History for March 7th</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-march-7th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 23:42:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-march-7th/</guid>
      <description>Digital History – March 7 I am liking Richard White a lot. I like the guy right away. His first map is even interesting. I still found something to be contrary about – “what is often clear enough in French becomes fashionably murky in English.” I do like that line but I’m gonna say it’s not fashionable; it’s just murky. Like when you try to watch a French movie and you get to the end and your just mad – murky with loose ends whipping around in the wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MapWarper</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/mapwarper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 18:20:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/mapwarper/</guid>
      <description>MapWarper The ability to overlay an old map on top of a new one is genius. For me, I can see where the best chance to see historical buildings in a city by taking an old map and warping it to fit on a current map. The most notable change to the Omaha map that I used, was the change in the river. Not only was the river in a different position but some parts of the city, on the old map, were not even there anymore due to what seems reasonable to assume, that the river had flooded out the buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airtable Tool</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/airtable-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 23:27:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/airtable-tool/</guid>
      <description>Airtable My database ended up a bit smaller than what we started with. I could not find a good way to insert the transcript of the letters. Any copy ended up giving me 18 more records with the transcript spread over all of them. Not only that, but they were also un-readable so it was not useful that way. I did discover that if I add to the transcript field itself, “long text,” it did not make multiple records but I still had to type in transcripts by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital History for Feb 28th</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-feb-28th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 23:13:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-feb-28th/</guid>
      <description>Digital History for Feb 28 Right off the bat I would say that the Spreadsheet Thinking vs Database Thinking would be great to have side by side with the OpenRefine class. I can’t help but think back to my skepticism of OpenRefine. I think I said something along the lines of it’s being just a spreadsheet, but reading this article makes things click into place. I was feeling better about things in general, until I read the comments, and now I’m appropriately back in my confidence-shaken place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital History for Feb 21st</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-feb-21st/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 22:53:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-feb-21st/</guid>
      <description>Digital History for Feb 21 I can’t believe Corbis would copy write a free picture. At first I thought that maybe they were trying to keep someone from taking their whole page but to put the watermark over the picture? Wtf? How infuriating. That must be bogus. Good luck taking anyone to court for a picture they got off of the government website. Putting that watermark over the picture must mean absolutely nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital History for Feb 14th</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-feb-14th/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 22:47:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/digital-history-for-feb-14th/</guid>
      <description>Digital History – for Feb 14th The first article gave me the impression that Rosenzweig really wants to save and preserve everything. On p 742 he mentions that emails and their attachments are not searchable? I had to re-read this in wonderment as to who cares. Maybe he wants to save every text ever sent too. And their attachments! Does he know what kind of attachments he would be saving?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 22:32:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week4/</guid>
      <description>OpenRefine What is challenging about the software? The software needs some UI work but other than that I think I may have had the wrong file of data or messed up with something early on. Hard to say since both files I entered as a new project did not match up with what the tutorial was talking about. I am skeptical of this tutorial. My UX on that tutorial is very low and I computer all day, so I’m not a complete idiot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week3p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 22:09:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week3p2/</guid>
      <description>The Lost Museum When I first found myself on their home page a video immediately started up explaining the Lost Museum as Barnum’s American Museum. The music in the background was so pronounced, and markedly bad, that I wondered if it was being used because it was an authentic recording. I did not find any such thing but did find a couple people credited for music in the About Us section, which did seem to give a wide berth of recognition to anyone involved in the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week3p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 22:07:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week3p1/</guid>
      <description>Digital History Reflection Week 3 I don’t like the victim-like tone of the first article. “Many many fields” ug, please. Don’t use the same word twice when trying to make your point. “We need a more broad definition of digital history work to surface the involvement of women employed at non-academic organizations.” There would be so many more men that would also emerge here but that wouldn’t be fair would it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week2</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 21:56:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week2/</guid>
      <description>Digital History - Week 2 Here are a few thoughts about our readings. First, I find it strange that “Time on the Cross” would use data from one plantation as the norm for all plantations. Maybe I read something wrong, but those authors are a prime example of misuse and misapplication of data that is subjective to multiple interpretations. There are common problems in statistics with taking biased human opinions and trying to make statistical data out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 21:47:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/week1/</guid>
      <description>Digital History - Week 1 The first thing I had to note the second I read it was in Friedman’s “Electric Dreams” on page 27. Friedman mentions John Perry Barlow’s writing of “Declaration of Independence for Cyberspace.” The second I read that title I had an immediate feeling of angry bitterness. That very phrase is null and void right now. Then Barlow says “the digital age cannot be denied or stopped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>My First Post Content</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hugo and Github Like Good Friends</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/using-hugo-and-github-like-good-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 19:56:54 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com/post/using-hugo-and-github-like-good-friends/</guid>
      <description>Using Hugo with Github Hugo is the program that compiles your web content (aka posts) into a website.
Hugo is completely separate from Github. Not related in any way.
All Hugo does is help you make a pretty website.
So, we can go to our terminal and enter the site directory by issuing the command
cd ~/Documents/digitalhistory.orphicoasis8.com  Now we can use any text editor or VS code to edit our posts</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>